Guide to the Jack O'Brien Papers AIA.067
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III: Belfast Project (Boston College & IRA Tapes), 2011-2015; 1.27 Linear Feet in 12 folders in a legal sized manuscript box and 11 folders in a second legal sized manuscript box
  This series focuses on Boston College's 2001 "Belfast Project," which was an oral history project focused on the Troubles. The Belfast Project interviewed former Provisional IRA members such as Dolours Price and Anthony McIntyre, both of whom recounted their experiences in the IRA. This series mostly contains materials related to the 2011 controversy surrounding the Police Service of Northern Ireland (PSNI) and British government subpoenaing the Belfast Project's transcripts in connection with the abduction and murder of Jean McConville in 1972. The series documents the outrage experienced by the Irish American community and supporters of Boston College by the PSNI and British government's actions, as well as the legal ramifications of the subpoena.
  This series contains newspaper clippings, correspondence, legal documents, emails, press statements, and memorandum.
  - ACLU Brief, 2012 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Ancient Order of the Hibernians Brehon Law Society, 2012-2013 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Boston College vs. British Government Subpoena, 2011 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Boston College Statement to Supporters, 2012 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Boston College Subpoena in New York City/Schumer Staff Meeting, 2011 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - "Commentary U.S. Role in British Request for Boston College", 2011 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Ancient Order of Hibernians to Members of the U.S. Government, 2011-2012 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Dornan and Associated PLLC, 2012 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - U.S. Senate and House of Representatives, 2012 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Emails, 2011-2014 (Box 31, Folder 15-16)
  - "Getting Gerry Adams: Norman Baxter's Long Crusade", 2012 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Irish American Unity Conference Statements, 2012-2013 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Legal Briefs - Supreme Court of United States, 2011-2012 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Legal Documents - Ed Moloney/Anthony McIntyre vs. Eric Holder/John T. McNeil, 2012 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Legal Document - First Affidavit of Ed Moloney, 2012 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Letter from American Sociological Association regarding Belfast Project, 2016 (Box 65, Folder 18)
  - Magazine Photocopy - History Ireland, 2012 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Memorandum - "Action Requested, Boston College Subpoenas", 2011 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Motion of Trustees of Boston College to Quash Subpoenas, 2011 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Newsclippings, 2011-2015 (Box 32, Folder 8-9)
  - Press Statements, 2011-2013 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Statement by the Council of American Sociological Association, 2012 (Box 32, Folder 11)
- Series IV: Monuments and Commemorations, 1861-2020 (inclusive), 1986-2009 (bulk); 3.27 Linear Feet in 4 legal sized manuscript box, 2 folders in a legal sized manuscript box, 19 folders in an additional legal sized manuscript box, 1 poster in rolled storage, 3 folders in an oversized box, 7 audiovisual items in a media box, 1 item in a card box, and 1 folder in a shared flat box; 11.85 Gigabytes on 3 CD-R discs and 4 DVD-R discs
  This series focuses upon Jack O'Brien's involvement and interest in monuments commemorating Irish individuals, as well as important events in Irish history. Topics include, but are not limited to the establishment of Irish Brigade monuments at Gettysburg and Antietam, the General Thomas Francis Meagher monument, creation of Robert Emmet Park, as well as the Commodore John Barry Memorial and Barry Gate at the U.S. Naval Academy in Annapolis, Maryland.
  Materials in this series include emails, fundraising financial logs, postcards, correspondence, flyers, architectural drawings, commemorative programs, photographs, brochures, newsclippings, CDs, VHS tapes, DVDs, a small sculpture, banners, flags, and posters.
  The materials in this series have been arranged alphabetically and themetically, when possible.
  - 9th Massachusetts and 28th Massachusetts Infantry Regiment, 2004 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - 63rd, 69th, 88th New York Irish Brigade, 1861, 1987-2006 (Box 32, Folder 13, Box 33, Folder 1)
  - 69th Regiment N.Y.S.M. Poster, undated (Box 61)
  - The Fighting 69 - 69th New York Infantry Regiment, 1987-1989, 1995-2019 (Box 33, Folder 1, Box 58, Folder 10)
  - 140th New York Infantry Monument and Patrick Henry O'Rorke, 2002-2003 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - 1916-2016 Centennial Committee (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Archbishop John J. Hughes Memorial, 2015 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Civil War Related Postcards, undated (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Colonel Dennis Heenan Memorial, 2009 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Catholic War Veteran's National Headquarters, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Colonel John Fitzgerald, 2012, 2018-2019 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Commodore John Barry Memorial Project, 1992-2018 (Box 33, Folder 9, Box 34, Folder 1-3, Box 64, Folder 13, Box Shared Tamiment 080, Folder 7)
  - Father William Corby (Chaplain, Irish Brigade) Statue, 2001-2016 (Box 34, Folder 4-5)
  - Photographs and Postcards -- Father William Corby (Chaplain, Irish Brigade) Statue, 2001 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Fenian Memorial Committee of America, 2020 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - General Michael Corcoran Memorial, 1990 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - General Thomas Francis Meagher Monument, 1996-1997, 2004-2011 (Box 34, Folder 9, Box 35, Box 58, Folder 8, Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Gettysburg, 1991, 1999, 2001-2005; cuid42451 (Box 35, Folder 3-5, Box 36, Folder 3, Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_AIA_067_ER_15)
  - Gettysburg (Irish Cultural Society), 2005; cuid42452 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_AIA_067_ER_11)
  - Irish Memorial Gettysburg, 1900, 1986-1987, 1990-1997, 2001-2006; cuid42466 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_AIA_067_ER_14, Box 36, Folder 1-2)
  - Irish Monument Project at Gettysburg, 2006; cuid42453 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_AIA_067_ER_5)
  - Irish Statues, 2016 (Box 65, Folder 15)
  - Great Hunger Memorials, 2004-2005, 2017-2018 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - High Cross Monument Co., 1994 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Irish American Veterans and the Korean War Memorial, 2001-2004, 2017 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Irish Brigade Association of Virginia, 1998 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Irish Brigade Monument - Antietam, 1962, 1987-2003 (Box 36, Folder 8-9, Box 59, Box Shared Tamiment 088, Vhs 067.0001 - 067.0002)
  - Irish Brigade Flag - 1st Regiment, undated (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Irish Monument Activities of Jack O'Brien and John E. McInerney, undated (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - The Irish Shrine at Lemmon Street, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - The Irish Vietnam Veterans Memorial Project, undated (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - The Irish Volunteer (Newsletter of the Irish Brigade Association), 1991-2000 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - James McKay Rorty and Battery B 1st New York Artillery, 1993, 2005-2006 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Marin Hogan Gravestone Unveiling, 2015 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Michael Collins Memorial, 2002 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - 20th Annual Michael Flannery Testimonial Awards Dinner, 2016 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - O'Donovan Rossa Funeral Re-enactment, 2015 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Photographs - 3rd Brigade 5th Corp Army of the Potomac Monument, 2001 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Photographs - 9th Massachusetts Infantry at Gettysburg Monument, 1999 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Photograph - 69th Pennsylvania Infantry Regiment Monument, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Photographs - 116th Pennsylvania Infantry Monument, 1999 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Photographs - Colonel Patrick O'Rourke Monument, 2001 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Reverand Patrick McCabe, 2019 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Robert Emmet Park and Memorial, 1966, 2013-2019 (Box 37, Folder 15, Box 65, Folder 25)
  - Robert Emmet Statue Rededication, 2016; cuid42454 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_AIA_067_ER_13)
  - St. Patrick's Chapel Historical Society, Inc., undated (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Thomas Devlin Reilly Memorial, 2004-2018 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - The Thompson Battalion Memorial Project, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - USS Michael Murphy, 2012 (Box 37, Folder 19)
- Series V: Ancient Order of Hibernians (AOH), 1880-2020 (inclusive), 1972-2012 (bulk); 3.65 Linear Feet in 6 legal sized manuscript box, 3 folders in a legal sized manuscript box, 2 folders in an additional legal sized manuscript box, 3 items in a card box, 2 audiovisual items in a media box, and 1 folder in an oversized box; 2.95 Gigabytes on 1 DVD-R disc and 1 CD-R disc
  This series focuses upon the history, activities, and legacy of the Ancient Order of the Hibernians (AOH), as well as Jack O'Brien's involvement with this organization. Materials include official memorandum, newsletters, AOH election materials, social invitations, emails, correspondence, posters, DVDs, booklets, photographs, commemorative coin, badges, convention materials, press releases, documents related to the Ladies Ancient Order of Hibernians (LAOH), as well as copies of the National Hibernian Digest, the official newspaper of the Ancient Order of Hibernians.
  - Address of Honorable Robert E. Sweeney Congressman at Large for the State of Ohio Before the Ancient Order of the Hibernians in America, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Ancient Order of Hibernians, 2008-2009, 2016 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - AOH 175th Anniversary, 2011 (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - AOH 175th Anniversary Coin, 2011 (Box 59)
  - AOH Application and Photographs, 2006 (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - AOH Badge, undated (Box 59)
  - AOH Board Erin, 2007 (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - AOH By-Laws, 1962, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - AOH By-Laws of the State Board of the District of Columbia (Draft), 2011 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - AOH Charles Carroll Div #2, 1977-1979, 1991-1992 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - AOH Conventions, 1972, 2003-2013 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - AOH Convention Programs, 1996, 2000, 2013 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - AOH and LAOH 1916 Rising Centenary Membership Album, 2016 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - AOH-LAOH Convention Programs, 1996, 2006, 2012 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - AOH e-Newsletters, 2016-2019 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - AOH Irish Yearbook, 1996 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - AOH John F. Kennedy Divison 5, 1994-2012, 2017-2020 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - AOH Ladies' Auxiliary, 1979 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - AOH Members, undated (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - AOH Membership Albums, 2012-2013 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - AOH National Board, 1988, 1990, 1996, 2002 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - AOH National Christmas Appeals, 2011, 2020 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - AOH Office of the National Historian, undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - AOH "Proud to Be an Irish American" Coaster, undated (Box 59)
  - AOH South Carolina Stateboard Directory, 2004 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - AOH Tyrone Division, 2017 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Buttons, undated (Box 47, Folder 29, Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Charities and Missions Honor Roll, undated (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Constitution, 2000 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Convention DIstrict of Columbia State Board, 2007-2011; cuid42465 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1990-2011 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Dedication of AOH Medal of Honor Monument, 1985; cuid42455; 2.9 Gigabytes (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_AIA_067_ER_7)
  - District of Columbia State Board Convention, 2004, 2007 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Division 39 Newsletter, 2011 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Dr. Sean MacBride Humanitarian Award, 1989, 2005 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Easter Rising Commemoration, 2015 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Election Materials, 1996, 2000, 2012, 2014 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Emails, 2011-2017 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Great Hunger Commemoration, 2000 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Grosse-Ile, Quebec, 2009 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Hibernians, 2009; cuid42456 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_AIA_067_ER_8)
  - The Hibernian Heart (Pictorial History of the AOH), 2012 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - The Hibernian Life newsletter, 1988-1990 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Historical Happenings, 2003 (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - History of the Ancient Order of Hibernians, 2001 (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Irish Testimonial Dinner, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - John Cardinal D'Alton, Div 3, 2000 (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Ladies Ancient Order of Hibernians Centennial Celebration Book, 1994 (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Martin Kelly - Experience on 9/11/01, undated (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Memos and Circulars, 1982, 1986, 1993, 2003, 2011, 2017 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - The Michigan Hibernian, 2004 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Molly Maguires and the AOH, 2003 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Name Tags, 2002, 2004 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - National President's Testimonial Dinner Programs, 2003, 2013, 2019 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Newsclippings, 1996, 2002-2004, 2006, 2013 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Newspapers - National Hibernian Digest, 1979-2000 (Box 40, Folder 8-10, Box 41, Folder 1-5, Box 42)
  - Northern Ireland, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Patrick J. Haltigan, 2018 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Photographs - AOH 84th Biennial Convention, Cleveland Ohio, 1988 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Photographs - Hibernian Muse, 1982, 1986-1988 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Photographs - Pro-Life Rally, 2011 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Political Education Committee, 2006 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Posters, undated (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Press Releases, 2016 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Project Crossmaglen, 2012 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - The Providence Visitor, 1880 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Reports, 1996, 2000, 2015 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Shillelagh Sentinel, 2012-2017 (Box 43, Folder 12, Box 65, Folder 26)
  - Social Events, Programs, Flyers, and Invitations, 1978, 1987-1988, 1990, 1996, 2008-2019 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Solidarity Day 1988 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - St. Patrick's Day Banquet & Ball Programs, 1990-1991 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - St. Patrick's Staff, 1983 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Thomas Gilligan, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - US President's Profiles, 1976 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Wreath Laying Ceremony - John F. Kennedy, 2010-2011 (Box 43, Folder 19)
- Series VI: Irish History, 1908-2020 (inclusive), 1986-2018 (bulk); 2.36 Linear Feet in 3 legal sized manuscript box, 1 folder in an oversized box, 1 artifact in a card box, 3 folders in a shared flat box, and 14 folders in a legal sized manuscript box
  This series reflects Jack O'Brien's interest in Irish history and focuses on many topics such as the 1916 Easter Rising, Fenian movement, the Great Famine in Ireland, the role of Irish and Irish American citizens during the American Civil War, the history of Irish and British relations, John F. Kennedy, World War I, and Grosse Ile (a Canadian Island that served as a refuge for Irish immigrants escaping the Great Famine).
  Materials in this series include brochures, news clippings, magazine articles, photographs, booklets, a DVD, and posters.
  - "180 Years Ago: O'Connell Launches Catholic Emancipation Efforts", 2003 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - "1847: A Chronicle of Genius, Generosity, and Savagery", 2016 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - 1916 Easter Rising, 1972-1974, 1984-1987, 2011-2016 (Box 44, Folder 3, Box 64)
  - 1916 Easter Rising Commemoration Pins, 2016 (Box 59)
  - 1916 Easter Rising Commemoration Poster, 1986 (Box 61)
  - 1916 Commemorative Journal - 100th Anniversary (Irish National Caucus), 2016 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - 1918 Commemorative Journal - 100th Anniversary of Irish National Caucus, 2018 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - "America's First Patriot Act", 2003 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - "An American Irish and Irish American Anniversary", 2017 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - American Irish Historical Society, 1941, 2004 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - American Revolution, undated (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - "The Amistad Connection", 2003 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - "Ancient Map of Ireland Discovered", 1987 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - The Ancient Music of Ireland, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - "The Anglo-Irish Treaty: The Death of the Dream", 2001 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Battle of Homestead (1892), undated (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Bloody Monday (Aug 6, 1855), 2005 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Book Excerpt - A Hidden Phase of American History: Ireland's Part in America's Struggle for Liberty, 1921 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Book Excerpt - The Irish in the American Revolution and their Early Influence in the Colonies, 1908 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - "A Brave and Generous People: Washington's St. Patrick's Day Proclamation of 1780", 2015 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Brexit and the MacBride Principles, 1993-2021 (Box Shared Tamiment 165, Folder 5)
  - Cartoon - "Notes for a history of Ireland", undated (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Catalpa (Whaling Ship), undated (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Celebrating a Centenary of Women's Suffrage and Representation in Parliament (booklet), 2018 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Civil War, 1959, 1986-2013 (Box 44, Folder 21-22, Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Civil War Records in the New York State Archives, undated (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Clan Na Gael, undated (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - "Concise History of Ireland's Woes...and to Whom Due", 1991 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - "The Coup, Then and Now: The Enemies of Humanity Try to Give Trump the JFK Treatment", 2017 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - "Crime of Britain", 2017 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - "Crucial Victory on Lake Champlain - 9/11/1814", 2018 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Dail Eireann Debate - Friday, 9 May 1919, 2018 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - "Dawn on the Irish Coast or the Exile's Return", undated (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - David McCullough, 2010 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - "A Day in Capitan Sarmiento", 2004 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - "Debunking a Myth: The Irish Were Not Slaves, Too", 2017 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - "Declassified FBI Files on Noraid - Part One (1972)", 2017 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - "Democracy in Ireland", 2017 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Dreamers of Dreams - Portraits of the Irish in America (Book Cover), undated (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Dublin After the Six Days' Insurrection: Thirty-One Pictures from the Camera of Mr. T.W. Murphy, undated (Box 64, Folder 15)
  - "The Economic Case for Irish Unity", 2015 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Eight Centuries of England in Ireland: A Synopsis of Irish History, 2001 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - "Eiri in Airde: Colonialism Summed Up", 2018 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - "The English in Ireland abd the Practice of Massacre", 2015 (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - "The Epic History and Heritage of the Irish", 2011 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - "Europe and the Irish Monks", 2017 (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - "Exposing the Scotch-Irish Myth", undated (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - Falkland Islands, undated (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - The Famine Plot: England's Role in Ireland's Greatest Tragedy, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Fenian Movement, 1990-2018 (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - "A Few Vital Aspects in the Understanding of the History of the Irish in Ireland and America in the 17th and 18th Centuries", undated (Box 45, Folder 24)
  - Fort O'Brien, 2001 (Box 45, Folder 25)
  - The GAA and Irish Independence, undated; cuid42457 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_AIA_067_ER_1)
  - General James Rowan O'Beirne, 1994 (Box 45, Folder 26)
  - Great Famine/Great Hunger, 1997-2018 (Box 45, Folder 27)
  - Grosse-Ile, 1997, 2009 (Box 45, Folder 28)
  - "How Can 50 States Be Wrong?", 2005 (Box 45, Folder 29)
  - "The Immigrant Girls of the Arsenal Memorial", undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - "IRA in County Cork not Sectarian", 2017 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Ireland's Thatched Cottages, 2014 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - "Ireland's US Navy's War Brides", 2017 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - "Irish Declaration of Independence (1919)", undated (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Irish History: Yesterday & Today, 2016 (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - Irish Life Viking Adventure, 1988 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - "Irish Maps, Place Names, Clan Lands, and more!", 2014 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Irish Nationality Law, undated (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - "Irish Return and Old Favor, Helping Native Americans Battling the Virus", 2020 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Irish Slaves in the Caribbean (James Cavanaugh), undated (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - "It's a Celtic Feast", undated (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - James Joyce, 2017 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - James Connolly Poster, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 080, Folder 5)
  - Jeanie Johnston, 2013 (Box 46, Folder 12, Box Shared Tamiment 080, Folder 6)
  - "Jerome Connor: Irish America's Artistic Spokesman", 2016 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - John F. Kennedy, 2013-2017 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - John and James Haltigan - Irish and American Patriots, 2015-2019 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - John Martin (1812-1875), 2004 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - John Phillip Holland, 2008 (Box 65, Folder 16)
  - Journal of the American Irish Historical Society, 1913 (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Kevin Barry Poster, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 080, Folder 4)
  - Kilcolgan Hotel, 2008 (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - "Labor in Irish History", 2004 (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - "Martyrs of the Mines", 2008 (Box 46, Folder 20)
  - Michael Collins, 1922, 2002, 2006 (Box 46, Folder 21)
  - Michael Corcoran (1827-1863), undated (Box 46, Folder 22)
  - Michael Doheny (1805-1862), 1989 (Box 46, Folder 23)
  - Mount Olivet Cemetery, 2004 (Box 46, Folder 24)
  - "The Mystery of Duffy's Cut", 2013 (Box 46, Folder 25)
  - The Cut: The Journey of the Men and Women of Duffy's Cut, 2017; cuid42458 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_AIA_067_ER_3)
  - "The Nation Newspaper", 2004 (Box 46, Folder 26)
  - "Navy Historic Markers - WWI", 2018 (Box 46, Folder 27)
  - "Nazi Spies in Ireland During WWII", 2007 (Box 46, Folder 28)
  - "Northern Ireland: Stuck in the 19th Century", 2003 (Box 46, Folder 29)
  - "On Ireland, Wilson Looked the Other Way", 2016 (Box 46, Folder 30)
  - Operation Green (Ireland), 2007 (Box 46, Folder 31)
  - Plan Kathleen, 2007 (Box 46, Folder 32)
  - Pocket Guide to Northern Ireland, undated (Box 46, Folder 33)
  - "Politically Correct Iconoclasm: Violations of Federal Status, Attempt to Erase History", undated (Box 46, Folder 34)
  - Presidential History, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 35)
  - Revival of Irish Language, 1989, 2012 (Box 46, Folder 36)
  - Saint Elizabeth Ann Seton (1774-1821), undated (Box 46, Folder 37)
  - Shipwrecks of the Delaware Coast: Tales of Pirates, Squalls, and Treasure, 2010 (Box 46, Folder 38)
  - Shipwreck of the Faithful Steward, 2017 (Box 46, Folder 39)
  - Short History Essays, undated (Box 46, Folder 40)
  - "Sinn Fein Secret 1988 Report on Noraid", 2017 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - "The Smashing of the Van", 2017 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Soldaten on Fighting, Killing, and Dying: The Secret World War II Transcripts of German POWs, 2012 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Terence McSwiney, Lord Mayor of Cork (1879-1920), 2015 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Terry O'Sullivan (General President, Laborers' International Union of North America), 2017 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Treason/Felony Act 1848, 2004 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Ulysses S. Grant, 2004 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - United States Christian Commission, undated (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - The Unknown: The Untold Story of America's Unknown Soldier and WWI's Most Decorated Heroes Who Brought Him Home, 2018 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - "Why Are Some Massacres Privileged?", 2017 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - "Why Irish American History?", 2018 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - "Winston Churchill Sent the Black and Tans to Palestine", 2017 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - World War I, 2011 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Zaire River Expedition, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 14)
- Series VII: Jack O'Brien - Personal Materials, 1879-2020 (inclusive), 1971-2017 (bulk); 3.69 Linear Feet in 9 legal size manuscript boxes, 17 folders in an additional legal size manuscript box, 1 folder in an oversize box, 2 artifacts in a card box, 4 audio visual discs in a media box, 1 poster in rolled storage, 1 letter size half manuscript box, and 2 folders in a shared oversized box; 11.21 Gigabytes on 1 CD-R disc and 3 DVD-R discs